Inventory of the Jay H. Cerf papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Jay H. Cerf papers
1940-1974
76041
Hoover Institution Archives
5 manuscript boxes (2.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, reports, instructions, and memoranda, relating to American commercial and foreign policy. Includes the Ph.D. dissertation of J. Cerf, Blue Shirts and Red Banners (1957), relating to the East German communist youth organization, Freie deutsche Jugend.
Cerf, Jay H.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1976.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Director, Foreign Policy Clearing House, 1957-1961; United States assistant secretary of commerce, 1961-1963; manager, International Group, United States Chamber of Commerce, 1963-1969.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, reports, instructions, and memoranda, relating to American commercial and foreign policy. Includes the Ph.D. dissertation of J. Cerf, Blue Shirts and Red Banners (1957), relating to the East German communist youth organization, Freie deutsche Jugend.
Foreign Policy Clearing House.; Freie deutsche Jugend.; United States Chamber of Commerce.; United States. Department of Commerce.; United States--Commerce.; United States--Foreign relations.; Youth movements--Germany (East)
- Cerf general - Cerf resume, 1940-1971 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Cerf general - Diplomas, degrees, certificates of attendance, 1938-1970 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Cerf general - Cerf articles, not including articles written as offical of an organization, 1952-1965 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Cerf general - Foreign travel credentials, police registration, travel orders, passports, etc., 1949-1973 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Pre-1957 - Printed items while at UW, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Pre-1957 - Outgoing correspondence, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Pre-1957 - WWII navy correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Pre-1957 - 1941 Washington High School yearbook (Box-folder 1: 8)
- University of Wisconsin, 1940-1951 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Fullbright Award, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- Congressional fellowship, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Foreign Policy Clearing House - Berlin movie contract, 1954 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Foreign Policy Clearing House - Description and miscellany, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Foreign Policy Clearing House - Freshman seminars for congressmen, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Foreign Policy Clearing House - Princeton conference on the balance of payments, 1959 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Foreign Policy Clearing House - Alliance for Progress, 1960-1967 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- Foreign Policy Clearing House - Summaries of studies on foreign economic policy, 1959 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Foreign Policy Clearing House - "Strategy for the 60's", 1961 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- US Dept of Commerce - Salvador trip, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 11)
- US Dept of Commerce - Key reports, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- 1948 University of Wisconsin yearbook (Box-folder 2: 13)
- Cerf US Dept of Commerce photo album, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Dept of Commerce - Correspondence, etc., 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- Chamber of Commerce of the US - articles, etc. about Jay Cerf, 1962-1967 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Chamber of Commerce of the US - Correspondence etc., 1962-1970 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Chamber of Commerce of the US - Articles by Jay Cerf, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Miscellaneous speeches, meeting notes, etc., 1965-1968 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Pathfinder, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- Consultants International of Cambridge, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- Congratulatory letters & responses - Re: Pathfinder, 1969 (Box-folder 3: 9)
- American Political Science Association, 1971 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Annenberg, Ambassador Walter, 1969 (Box-folder 4: 2)
- Amroliwala, Cavas, 1967 (Box-folder 4: 3)
- Barghoorn, Frederick - Yale professor of political science, 1956-1963 (Box-folder 4: 4)
- Benton, Bill, 1956 (Box-folder 4: 5)
- Bowles, Chester, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 4: 6)
- Buchbinder, Hazel, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 4: 7)
- Federal City Club, 1968 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- Federal Union, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 9)
- Gale, A.R., 1971 (Box-folder 4: 10)
- Foreign Service - India invitation '66 & related correspondence, 1966 (Box-folder 4: 11)
- Harvard University, 1955-1970 (Box-folder 4: 12)
- Hays, Wayne L., 1956 (Box-folder 4: 13)
- Hodges, Luther, 1961 (Box-folder 4: 14)
- Humphrey, Hubert H., 1959-1971 (Box-folder 4: 15)
- Industrial College of the Armed Forces, ICAF, 1957 (Box-folder 4: 16)
- Johnson, Lyndon (Box-folder 4: 17)
- Kennedy, John F. (Box-folder 4: 18)
- Liang, Hsi Huey - Professor of history now at Vassar, 1959 (Box-folder 4: 19)
- Kirkpatrick, Evron, 1957 (Box-folder 4: 20)
- McCamy, James L., 1948-1967 (Box-folder 4: 21)
- Morse, Wayne, 1949 (Box-folder 4: 22)
- Mosely, Philip E., 1966-1968 (Box-folder 4: 23)
- Nation Press Club, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 4: 24)
- Nestingen, Ivan, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 2: 25)
- Norstad, Lauris, 1967 (Box-folder 4: 26)
- Orr, Edgar, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 4: 27)
- Praeger, Frederick A., 1957-1985 (Box-folder 4: 28)
- Parker, Daniel, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 4: 29)
- Richardson, Elliot, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 4: 30)
- Roadstead, Foundation, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 4: 31)
- Rockefeller, David, 1969 (Box-folder 4: 32)
- Stevenson, Adlai, 1952 (Box-folder 4: 33)
- Stokes, Donald E., 1969-1973 (Box-folder 4: 34)
- Trowbridge, A.B., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4: 35)
- Truman, Harry S., 1956 (Box-folder 4: 36)
- Udall, Stuart (Box-folder 4: 37)
- Wallace, Irving, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 4: 38)
- Weaver, John C., 1972 (Box-folder 4: 40)
- Washington Institute of Foreign Affairs (Box-folder 4: 39)
- Who's Who, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 4: 41)
- Vienna, 1959 - VIIth World Festival of Youth for Peace and Freedom (Box-folder 4: 42)
- Williams, Shirley & Bernard, 1972 (Box-folder 4: 43)
- Wilton Park, American Friends of, 1972 (Box-folder 4: 44)
- Wilton Park Conference, 1962 (Box-folder 4: 45)
- Wisconsin, University of, 1946-1950 (Box-folder 4: 46)
- Woodword, Robert, 1969 (Box-folder 4: 47)
- Yale University, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 4: 48)
- Yale University Press, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 4: 49)
- Increment August 1978 - "Blue Shirts and Red Banners," (Box-folder 5: 1-4)